<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[dianaphamhere]]></title>
  <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-21T12:28:11-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://dianapham.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Diana Pham]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[diana's take on what to learn]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/09/17/dianas-take-on-what-to-learn/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-17T16:14:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/09/17/dianas-take-on-what-to-learn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When picking the right language to learn, you’ve really got to think about what you want to do. If you want do web dev, do you want to be back-end, front-end or full stack? If you want to be a mobile dev, what OS do you want to work with: iOS, Android or Windows (cough)? If you wanna make games, do you want to make it for consoles, mobile or PCs? Also, where does money factor in in all of this? Are you switching careers to create things you’re passionate about or to get a salary increase?</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Web Dev</h3>

<p><strong>Ruby/Ruby on Rails</strong></p>

<p>Ruby on Rails has a huge community that’s rapidly growing (especially in the Seattle area (especially in the Startup community)). Normally, when you hear someone say they know Ruby, they’ll more than likely also know Ruby on Rails. I took the Ruby on Rails bootcamp (equivalent to a dev accelerator now) last year. It was difficult to learn mainly because I almost no experience with programming. However, Rails as a framework takes care of a lot for you and it’s pretty well organized with a bunch of documentation. A lot of people seem to learn Ruby, the language, while they learn Rails, the framework.</p>

<p>Ruby as a language is described as very pretty and easy to use. Semicolons are not required. People create libraries for Ruby and those libraries are called gems (get it? ruby. gem. yeah.). You’ll find yourself using a lot of gems. You can try writing some Ruby here in this short intro tutorial: <a href="http://tryruby.org/levels/1/challenges/0">http://tryruby.org/levels/1/challenges/0</a></p>

<p>And if you&rsquo;re up for it, get Rails running on your machine and try this out: <a href="http://guides.rubyonrails.org/getting_started.html">http://guides.rubyonrails.org/getting_started.html</a></p>

<p><strong>Python/Django</strong></p>

<p>I never learned Django because was sticking with Rails for web dev, but I did learn Python. A lot of people say that Python is more of a general programming language. It’s easy to make prototypes. I learned a bit of Python and liked it. I created some pretty neat games and learned a lot of logic from learning Python. There’s actually a free course going on right now on Coursera for Python if anyone wants to check that out: <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/interactivepython">https://www.coursera.org/course/interactivepython</a> This is one I watched when I learned Python. The instructors are these four old nerdy guys who are just adorably hilarious.</p>

<p>Since I don’t have any experience with Django, here are some resources:</p>

<p>For a general comparison of Django vs Rails, visit this link: <a href="http://forums.udacity.com/questions/100012806/why-web-startups-favor-ruby-rails-vs-python-django">http://forums.udacity.com/questions/100012806/why-web-startups-favor-ruby-rails-vs-python-django</a></p>

<p>For a technical comparison of Django vs Rails, visit this link: <a href="https://bernardopires.com/2014/03/rails-vs-django-an-in-depth-technical-comparison/">https://bernardopires.com/2014/03/rails-vs-django-an-in-depth-technical-comparison/</a></p>

<p><strong>Node.js</strong></p>

<p>Everyone I’ve meant who knows Node.js pretty much swears by it. The biggest argument is that JavaScript is already everywhere across the web, why not use it throughout the stack? I haven’t had the change to learn it yet, but seriously, apparently people get very hardcore about it once they learn it. Here’s an aptly named article: <a href="http://www.toptal.com/nodejs/why-the-hell-would-i-use-node-js">http://www.toptal.com/nodejs/why-the-hell-would-i-use-node-js</a></p>

<p><strong>Front-End Dev</strong></p>

<p>Honestly, I think everyone should be a front-end dev. And then if you want to learn back-end too, you’ll be a full stack developer. Anyway, to be a front-end dev, you for surely need to get really good at HTML/CSS/JS. Totally learn jQuery. If you decide you just want to be a web designer, you’ll have an easier time finding a job if you know HTML/CSS. This makes it easier for employers because instead of you just handing off a sketch to a developer, you can actually develop the code yourself. Then you know, the back end developer integrate all the other services and stuff.</p>

<p>Whether you chose to solely do front-end dev or back-end dev, I highly recommend knowing a fair amount of HTML/CSS/JS if you’re getting in web dev. Honestly, I feel like if you want to get a job quick, learning Rails is the way to go right now. From what I’ve gathered in my research, there’s just more companies using Rails than they are companies using Django or Node.js.</p>

<p>Alternatively, if you’re not super worried about what’s the most popular, there are a bunch of other languages and frameworks you could use to make websites, like the ASP.NET framework, AngularJS and others. I’m not a huge fan of sending people to Wikipedia, but this page actually has a really thorough outline of all the web application frameworks sorted by language: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_web_application_frameworks">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_web_application_frameworks</a></p>

<h3>Mobile Dev</h3>

<p>When creating mobile apps, you really have to be aware of how many devices there are in the world. The top OS hitters are iOS, Android and Windows Phone, but within each of those ecosystems, there’s a ton of devices with different resolutions and other hardware customizations. Responsive design is key.</p>

<p><strong>iOS</strong></p>

<p>HOLLA! I really like Obj-C and I’m liking Swift too as I’m learning it. Xcode, an IDE for OS X and iOS, makes it really easy to create projects. The GUI especially makes development much easier (I’m specifically talking about the storyboard). Obj-C’s syntax is enough to drive away a lot of developers, but once you get used to it, it’s not a big deal. Xcode is free to download if you have a Mac computer. It also comes with a simulator so you can test your apps. You do have to purchase a developer license to test on a physical device and submit to the App Store though. Sending out an iOS app to the App Store to be verified can take awhile especially if you have a ton of bugs and they send it back to you, but this is how Apple makes sure they’ve got better quality apps in the App Store. There are a ton of apps already in the App Store, but honestly, making iOS apps is the way you’re going to make more money. The way Apple sets up their user accounts, it’s so much easier for someone to accept purchasing an app. <a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/referencelibrary/GettingStarted/RoadMapiOS/">https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/referencelibrary/GettingStarted/RoadMapiOS/</a></p>

<p><strong>Android</strong></p>

<p>I think Android development was easy for me to pick up because I already learned iOS dev, but really you’re just learning another language’s syntax (Java in this case). The dev kit is free to install, but I found it was a more involved process than downloading Xcode. A good thing is you can develop Android apps on any type of computer (Mac, Windows, Linux). You can customize a lot on Android, which is great, but also can lead to a bunch of bugs and crashes. <a href="http://developer.android.com/training/index.html">http://developer.android.com/training/index.html</a></p>

<p><strong>Windows Phone</strong></p>

<p>The mobile market is saturated with iOS and Android; the Windows Phone really doesn’t compare. But to get things going, Microsoft throws out all sorts of incentives for developers to create apps for Windows Phone. I haven’t keep track of them lately, but they used to do things like give free phones to developers who submit their first app to the store. Or give $250 credit for developers who submit two apps. I dunno. It seems like they’re really grasping. Microsoft just bought Mojang though so I’m sure they’re going to try to get Minecraft on the Windows Phone to boost the popularity of the phone. In any case, while there aren’t many apps in their store, you could say that by submitting your own apps, you’d have more probability of visibility, but at the same time, that’s only visibility from an already low population of Windows Phone users. The language is predominately C#, but I believe you can also use C++. <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/ff402529">http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/ff402529</a></p>

<h3>Game Dev</h3>

<p>if you already know what type of games you want to make and/or what environment, then it&rsquo;ll be easier to figure out what language you should learn. if you want to make games for Xbox, you&rsquo;ll want to learn C#. if you want to make web games, learn JavaScript and check out HTML5 Canvas. if you wanna make games for iOS, learn Obj-C or Swift. if you wanna make games for Android, learn Java.</p>

<p>There are also programs that allow cross-platform publishing, but the code won&rsquo;t be native. Native code means that the programming language used to make the game is the same one the platform is running. (Obj-C for iOS, Java for Android). Games or any app will run faster if you&rsquo;re using native code. Anyway, if you want to check out making cross-platform games, check out Unity3d which mainly uses C#, Javascript or Boo, then converts to the other platforms. <a href="http://unity3d.com/">http://unity3d.com/</a></p>

<h3>In Summation</h3>

<p>If you&rsquo;re just starting out and don&rsquo;t know what you want to do, go to tech events and talk to people about what they do and what they learned to get there. Also, all the basic computer science stuff can be learned with any language. Once you excel at a certain language, you&rsquo;ll have the fundamental tools to learn another language and see which works best for you and what you want to make. The reason there are a ton of different languages is because some are better for some things than others, but they all basically contain the same concepts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[it's been a year]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/09/03/its-been-a-year/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-03T11:49:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/09/03/its-been-a-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I graduated from Code Fellows one year ago.</p>

<p>WOAHH.</p>

<p>I wrote a thingy for Code Fellows to post on their blog. You can read it
<a href="https://www.codefellows.org/blog/life-after-code-fellows-diana-pham-and-the-creation-of-dinohulk">here</a>.</p>

<p>I had two drafts. One was a philosophical look and the other was more of what actually happened in the past year. The latter got published. I&rsquo;m going to publish the philosophical one here. I dunno if anyone even visits this blog of mine anyway. I rarely post anything.</p>

<p>Blah blah excuses.</p>

<p>&mdash;</p>

<h3>Changing My Life: One Year Later</h3>

<p><em>Self Reflection</em></p>

<p>Every morning, I wake up and ask myself, “Did I make a good decision?” The decisions range from whether I should have ignored my five morning alarms or more serious matters such as should I have eaten that taco before bed. Self reflection is a big part of how I’ve gotten where I am today. I question who I am, where I am and whether I like any of that. Some call it doubt, I call it double checking.</p>

<p>Three and a half years ago, was it a good decision to drop college, leave home and start a new life in Seattle with only $14.12 in my bank account? Two years ago, was it a good decision to work two full time jobs with a constant flow of side gigs just to save up for “something” in the future? One year ago, was it a good decision to trust my life savings (of two years) to a newly founded startup that claimed they would help me change my life by teaching me how to program? Did I know the right people who could help me rough up this company if this turned out to be a scam?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>All my life I was told I wasn’t good enough or that I was too cocky; I was going to fail or that I was just lucky; I was going to regret everything or that I was ungrateful. Stoicism became my resolve. To this day, when I have these self reflections, I always wonder if I’m allowed to be proud of myself for my risky accomplishments or if I should just quietly be grateful I didn’t do more harm than good. But then I recall my time at Code Fellows and remember that I am as invincible as I will allow myself to be.</p>

<p><em>You Are Amazing</em></p>

<p>“We are not here to crank out code monkeys. We’re here to change lives.” &ndash; Will Little, July 2014</p>

<p>In just the first 15 minutes of taking a seat in that (initially thought to be sketchy) basement classroom, I relaxed and knew that I had made the right decision in embarking on this crusade towards self-sustaining fulfillment with the initial guidance from the remarkable staff at Code Fellows. Yes, I learned how to program coming from only one week’s worth of coding background before applying to the bootcamp. Yes, I learned how to get all up into social media and forums to make my name known on the internet. Yes, I learned where to find all the good tech events and how to network with a bunch of awesome people. But the most goddamn important thing I learned when I was at Code Fellows was that I am fucking amazing and no one can take that away from me.</p>

<p>I plowed through those eight weeks with an intensity I did not know I possessed. People told me learning how to program was going to be hard. They told me a rigorous eight week bootcamp was going to be super intense. Working nights and weekends while going to a this eight week programming bootcamp was downright insane. My friends who knew of my health issues said it was a bad time to take these risks. But I didn’t care what anyone said. I was ready to throw in everything I had for a chance to discover the world and a better me.</p>

<p><em>Be Curious</em></p>

<p>While I worked on my final project, a website to teach beginners how to program, <a href="http://www.tekkikat.com">tekkikat.com</a>, I started getting curious about other parts of the tech industry. There had to be more than just web development, right? What about mobile apps? What about console games? Those had to be programmed by people too, right? So I taught myself how to make an iOS app. I thought my instructors would be mad that I wasn’t solely working on my final project, but I was pleasantly surprised by their enthusiastic comments towards my simple “type your name, click the button then you’ll see ‘hello, [your name]” app. “Woah! This is awesome! Since you already know Ruby, did you know there’s this thing where you can use Ruby to make mobile apps too?” Instead of keeping me pigeonholed in web dev, they encouraged me to foster my curiosity and that’s what led to me starting my own company called <a href="http://www.dinohulk.com">DINOHULK</a>.</p>

<p>Officially a year later, I am grateful for my decision to join Code Fellows. I learned that there’s nothing wrong with believing you’re amazing and that being curious is nothing to be ashamed of. In the past year, I’ve traveled around teaching kids and adults the joys of programming. I’ve spoken at schools and events about my path into the tech field. I’ve written a bunch of stories about the little wonders of the world that I have discovered. Most people expect to obtain a grandiose career as a programmer after graduating a bootcamp. Although, I’m not some top notch programmer now, I still found an amazing career. My job is to be amazing, be curious and to inspire others do the same.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ME FEATURED IN GEEKWIRE]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/me-featured-in-geekwire/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T15:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/me-featured-in-geekwire</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m mildly famous!!! Check out this <a href="http://www.geekwire.com/2014/code-fellows-offer-women-ruby-rails-bootcamp/">article</a>!</p>

<p>So swag.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[THESE TYPES OF PEOPLE]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/these-types-of-people/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-16T12:50:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/these-types-of-people</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://dianapham.github.io/images/githubsongelitist.png" title="[github song elitist]" ></p>

<p>These types of people really bother me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RAD RANDY OPEN MIC]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/05/09/rad-randy-open-mic/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-09T11:43:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/05/09/rad-randy-open-mic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://dianapham.github.io/images/radrandyopenmic.png" title="[rad randy open mic]" ></p>

<p>Awww, yeahh! Check out <a href="http://www.dinohulk.com/radrandy/openmic">Rad Randy&rsquo;s Open Mic</a>!!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[happy bday me]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/05/01/happy-bday-me/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-01T17:41:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/05/01/happy-bday-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://dianapham.github.io/images/googlebday.png" title="[google cakes]" >
Cute, Google. Cute.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[portability]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/28/portability/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-28T22:05:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/28/portability</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve got a to find a way to post stuff on here without always having my laptop. Or a computer for that matter. Iono. I&rsquo;ll figure it out.</p>

<p>Been kinda depressed lately. MEH.</p>

<p>People. The sun. Spring. Pollen. Etc.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[UGH. Migraine.]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/25/ugh-migraine/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-25T21:23:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/25/ugh-migraine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I don&rsquo;t know why I get so many migraines. By definition, I believe they are chronic.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Science. Yeah!]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/24/science-yeah-slash/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-24T22:40:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/24/science-yeah-slash</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just a note to myself. Take a picture of that bookmark to go along with this post.</p>

<p>Also, add process in fixing broken laptop charger.</p>

<p>Today has been an exhausting day.</p>

<p>BUT I GOT THE JOB! I&rsquo;M GONNA BE A TECH/ROBOTICS INSTRUCTOR AT A SUMMER CAMP! YAYY!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boo.]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/24/boo/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-24T15:02:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/24/boo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m missing a package. 2/3 came in. What happened to the other one? BOOOOOO.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[XENA]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/23/xena/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-23T14:28:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/23/xena</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aw yeah!!!</p>

<p><img src="http://dianapham.github.io/images/xena2.png" title="[xena zoomed]" >
<img src="http://dianapham.github.io/images/xena1.png" title="[xena original size]" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anxiety]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/22/anxiety/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-22T23:36:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/22/anxiety</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had a mild anxiety attack earlier. The result of that is that my upper left side is searing in pain. LAMESIES.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s something to do with an adrenaline burst, tightly contracting muscles and an abundant acid production. Meh. Alls I know is I felt this feeling for something like three years and I really don&rsquo;t want to feel it anymore.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t really feel like talking about what happened for three years. It&rsquo;s not that I&rsquo;m not willing to, it&rsquo;s more like I have a ton of work I want to do so I don&rsquo;t really have time to babble one about that shit. However, I will talk a bit about what my anxiety attack was about earlier.</p>

<p>I have one friend here in Seattle that I&rsquo;d do anything for: my best friend in Seattle. He&rsquo;s my roommate now. A lot of people have claimed that we&rsquo;re dating and whatnot, but they&rsquo;re just being ignorant. I think of him as a brother. He&rsquo;s one of the first few people I met when I moved to Seattle. I didn&rsquo;t meet him right away as if I openly talked to him or anything. I actually hated him for the first year I knew him. He was such an asshole at work. But when I switched to a different department and ended up having to work with him, I realized he was a really good guy. He came off as an asshole because he needed to get his work done. And cuz &ldquo;someone&rdquo; needed to put people in their place.</p>

<p>We quickly became friends. We bonded over broski things like UFC, MMA and idiocy at work. I was sick though. I had bad mood swings. I was still trying to figure out my histamine issues. I was still getting hives and migraines. He&rsquo;d always be there though. He wouldn&rsquo;t go out of his way to comfort me, but if I ever needed help, he&rsquo;d be there. That&rsquo;s all I needed.</p>

<p>Sometimes I&rsquo;d go weeks not talking to him. Sometimes months. But everytime I reached out, he&rsquo;d be there. That&rsquo;s a lot to ask from most people. I don&rsquo;t know if it&rsquo;s his apathy that allows him to be like he is or whatever, but I don&rsquo;t really think about it anymore. We&rsquo;ve been through so much in our friendship (mostly because of my drama) that we&rsquo;re just friends now. It&rsquo;s accepted that we&rsquo;re friends. Like, forever.</p>

<p>So yeah. The difference with him compared to my other friends is that he&rsquo;s anti-social and apathetic. I feel like it&rsquo;d be difficult to hang out with him or talk to him if he wasn&rsquo;t in the immediate area. So that&rsquo;s what I was panicking about. He mentioned something about moving to Oregon at the end of the year.</p>

<p>UH. NO.</p>

<p>After a lengthy conversation filled with my dramatics, I believe I secured him staying in Seattle.</p>

<p>Thank gosh.</p>

<p>But yeah, I&rsquo;m dealing with the reprecussions of my anxiety attack now. It&rsquo;s annoying, but at least in the grand scheme of things, I still have my friend.</p>

<p>Yay.</p>

<p><img src="http://dianapham.github.io/images/friendship.png" width="450" title="[our friendship]" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adorbz]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/22/adorbz/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-22T13:49:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/22/adorbz</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://dianapham.github.io/images/dinohulkcharpixel.png" title="[dinohulk characters!]" ><br/><br/>
Aren&rsquo;t these just adorable?</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m really glad I randomly started doing pixel art again. It makes me feel like I have a chance at making that game I wanted to make years ago.</p>

<p>I wish when I had more support when I was younger to do things that I wanted. I aspired to do some many things with technology. I really wanted to get into game development, but I had no idea how to go about it. It sucks I wasn&rsquo;t persistant about it. Iono. I understand why I stopped trying though. I was tired of people using me. I knew the better I got at doing things like photo editing, the more people would make me do stuff for them.</p>

<p>My mom would always wake me up at 5 or 6 in the morning and make me edit pictures for her. It was really annoying. I&rsquo;d have to clean up the cat&rsquo;s poop and then go work for my mom. I remember always being really hungry.</p>

<p>When our computers started glitching out, I kinda just left it. I didn&rsquo;t care anymore. I didn&rsquo;t want to work for her anymore. Plus, she already told me to not get into computer work. So like, whatever right?</p>

<p>Meh.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s hard to be indifferent. I get so bitter and angry. I don&rsquo;t like it when I&rsquo;m like that. So I become indifferent. But that in turn comes with a price.</p>

<p>MEH.</p>

<p>Whatever. I can still do what I want. I&rsquo;m not stuck there anymore.</p>

<p>On a brighter not, I finally cut my fingernails. Heyoo!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m glad I met my boyfriend and then his friends. They&rsquo;re all in game dev and it&rsquo;s just a really nice community to be associated with. I&rsquo;m like, going full circle into what I used to want to do. I guess now it&rsquo;s still what I wanna do. So yeah. YEAH.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[World of Imagination]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/21/world-of-imagination/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-21T23:45:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/21/world-of-imagination</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve always been interested in pixel art. Since like iono, my elementary school years. Whenever we got our first Gameboy. Years later, I got really obsessed with Harvest Moon Friends of Mineral Town. I really wanted to create my own RPG that involved cooking. Basically everything that Harvest Moon did with their kitchen except just have the game centered around that instead of farming. I remember thinking, &ldquo;How hard is it to build a game?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Hah.</p>

<p>Hah.</p>

<p>Yeah. It&rsquo;s kinda hard. I drafted the characters and environment, but I had no idea how to get anything on the computer. Like, &ldquo;programming&rdquo; didn&rsquo;t cross my mind at all. I had no idea what to do. Then freaking Cooking Mama came out and I was like, UGH.</p>

<p>I still kinda wanna make the game though. Stardew Valley is still in the development. I can&rsquo;t wait until that&rsquo;s released.</p>

<p>Anyway, here&rsquo;s another thing of pixel art I made:</p>

<p><img src="http://dianapham.github.io/images/dianaPixelDonut.png" title="[pixelated!]" ></p>

<p>Reference:<br/><br/>
<img src="http://dianapham.github.io/images/dianaDonut.png" title="[not pixelated!]" ></p>

<p>Pretty cool, huh? :D</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ghost Ninja]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/21/ghost-ninja/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-21T23:01:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/21/ghost-ninja</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m kind of hiding from the world right now. But like, still being awesome. Like this ghost ninja:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://dianapham.github.io/images/ghostninja.jpg" title="[AW YEAH IM SO STRONG]" ></p>

<p>Pixel art is fun. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revitalize]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/21/revitalize/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-21T10:08:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/21/revitalize</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My fingernails are too long. I don&rsquo;t know how most girls have such long nails. It hinders typing too much. Such a hassle it is.</p>

<p>I finally backed up my computer the other day so I&rsquo;m going to reinstall everything hopefully today or tomorrow.</p>

<p>I have 1000 buttons on the table. I think I need more. Haha. Button sales seem to be going well. A lot of customers seem to like the more down to earth characters. I&rsquo;m still contemplating the direction in which I want to lead my company. It&rsquo;s frustrating not having the support I deem necessary, but whatever. If there&rsquo;s anything about me that y&#8217;all should know, it is that I don&rsquo;t take shit from anyone. There we go, curse away.</p>

<p>I really don&rsquo;t like working for inconsiderate assholes. I kinda grew up in that sort of environment and it&rsquo;s just unnecessary. It&rsquo;s stupid. It&rsquo;s annoying. And all in all, it&rsquo;s tiring.</p>

<p>I keep having flashbacks.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I&rsquo;ve contemplated whether I still want to keep this blog as just a tech-related blog or not. Whatever. I want people to know who I am. I don&rsquo;t see myself trying to apply to any big companies anytime soon. And if I ever do and they pass me cuz of what I write here, then whatever. I&rsquo;m kind of beyond the point of dealing with people who don&rsquo;t care about me and don&rsquo;t give me a chance. I will work my ass off for whatever I care about. But you know, that&rsquo;s the thing. I have to care first. So if you don&rsquo;t care about me then I&rsquo;m not going to care about you.</p>

<p>My mom once told me that if I wanted respect, I had to respect people first. She told me this while we were in her car on the driveway of our house. She was in the driver seat as I was in the back seat behind the passenger seat. The passenger seat was always full of papers. Painting the picture of the scene doesn&rsquo;t do much for this particular story, but it helps me remember. I&rsquo;ve been pushing everything back way too much. I need to let it out now. Cuz you know, I need therapy.</p>

<p>Anyway. There we were in driveway. We were about to leave to this Sunday Vietnamese School that she taught at. I took classes at this school, but seriously? I did not understand the language. I failed so many classes. She always asked the teachers to let me go on and that she&rsquo;d &ldquo;help&rdquo; me. Meh. I still failed. Eventually, I wasn&rsquo;t allowed to move up unless I actually passed and iono. It was agonizing. All these other little kids would pass and a fresh batch of kids would enter while I stayed. I felt so dumb. The problem was that they spoke the language at home so they understood all these words. I didn&rsquo;t. I could read and write, but comprehension was out the window.</p>

<p>I keep going on all these tangents. My writing kind of sucks now. MEH.</p>

<p>Whatever. Basically, I fumbled my way through all the grades and eventually made it to the last grade; the class that my mom taught. WELL! She said there was no way I was going to pass her class so I had to go up to the office to work for all the teachers. Oh great. Yeah, lemme go ahead and copy all the homework for the whole school in two hours. Lemme make y&#8217;all tea. Yeah, okay, I&rsquo;ll set out your food and clean up after you. Okay, I&rsquo;ll make sure all your supplies are in stock and clean. Okay, I&rsquo;ll go deliver all these papers and talk to people in a mangled version of your language so they&rsquo;ll get mad at me and call me stupid.</p>

<p>People always thought I was bitter and angry. Fuck yeah I was bitter and angry. But I was also fucking sad. I felt pathetic.</p>

<p>One day, I was sitting in front of stacks of papers that were supposed to go out to every class in the school. Some teacher came over and asked me in their language, &ldquo;Do we have to organize these papers?&rdquo; I was trying to form the words to say, &ldquo;I already organized them.&rdquo; I didn&rsquo;t want to sound stupid so I took care to form the sentence in my mind before I said it. It look like ten seconds for each word. But no. Don&rsquo;t give me any goddamn time to not sound dumb. Go ahead and call me dumb. And angry. And worthless. Yes, I fucking organized those three hundred pieces of paper. Fuck you. You go pass them out.</p>

<p>Respect. &ldquo;You have to respect people if you want them to respect you.&rdquo; Doesn&rsquo;t it work the other way too? No one respected me so why did I have to respect them? I don&rsquo;t care if they were older or had &ldquo;higher positions.&rdquo; If you treat me like shit, I&rsquo;m not going to like you. Why should I respect you? Wasn&rsquo;t it enough I was your little bitch? Your &ldquo;office assistant.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Yeah, I&rsquo;m still fucking bitter. People tell me it&rsquo;s over. That I don&rsquo;t have to think about it anymore. Well that&rsquo;s not true. I fucking remember it every single night. I cry and hide in closets. In two weeks, I&rsquo;m going to turn 24. Aren&rsquo;t I an adult? Why do I still feel like a child?</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t know what I ever did to make people not like me. I always did what I was told. Was it a misunderstanding? Fuck yeah it was. Thanks for not trying to help me though.</p>

<p>I feel something boiling inside. I haven&rsquo;t felt it in years because I shoved it down to survive. I&rsquo;m afraid I&rsquo;m going to explode.</p>

<p>I think the point of all that was that if someone reads all that and doesn&rsquo;t want to work with me then whatever. I really don&rsquo;t care. Culture fit is important to me. Being human is important to me. Keeping it real and all that.</p>

<p>When I give talks and stuff, I allude to how I had a rough childhood. I mumble something about how I&rsquo;m an angry person and everyone chuckles. It&rsquo;s pretty funny. I usually chuckle too. I really admire people who go through hardships and make the most of them. That&rsquo;s what I try to do all the time. I try to joke about things that happen. I use humor to handle everything. Sometimes it&rsquo;s too sarcastic and dry for people. Too much dark humor for the general public. But I need it. And I need to vent.</p>

<p>I really don&rsquo;t want to blow up.</p>

<p>So yeah. Here&rsquo;s me trying to reset again. To move on the correct way. Dealing with my issues instead of shoving them down. Three years ago, it was what I needed. I knew it&rsquo;d come back and haunt me. But I needed to survive. I couldn&rsquo;t deal with my past. Now that I&rsquo;m &ldquo;surviving,&rdquo; all of the past is crawling up to reach me. I&rsquo;m done just surviving. I think it&rsquo;s time to live.</p>

<p>Man, that got all mushy there didn&rsquo;t it? Gross.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m proud of everything I&rsquo;ve accomplished. I&rsquo;ve met a ton of awesome people. I want to keep meeting awesome people. I want to excel at everything I do just like I have been. I&rsquo;ve proven I can make it. Fuck the past. It wants to creept up so I&rsquo;ll throw it all out there, but after that I&rsquo;m gonna be all like, &ldquo;yo man, you had your time. get outta hurr.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m so lame sometimes. el oh el oh el.</p>

<p>Okay. Bye.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Curious]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/19/curious/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-19T15:14:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/19/curious</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What do you want, Beezy?</p>

<p>I almost cursed there. I&rsquo;ve been trying to cut down on that because curse too much. Also, if I&rsquo;m writing books for kids, what would it look like if I&rsquo;m cursing like a trucker? Actually, during my bootcamp, I remember people always remarking about how cursing is just part of the culture. Thank gosh.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m contemplating what I want to do with my company. I want to do A LOT. But I don&rsquo;t know if the avenue I&rsquo;m taking is the right way or not. It&rsquo;s really frustrating.</p>

<p>Also, I really don&rsquo;t like typing/reading white text over black. It hurts my eyes. I dunno if I&rsquo;d like it if I changed the template of SublimeText2 though. I like keeping things the standard way. GAH.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m going to make a list to try some markdown:</p>

<ul>
<li>I don&rsquo;t like wearing socks without shoes.</li>
<li>Toe segregation scares me.</li>
<li>Blueberry muffins are yummy, but blueberry cakes are weird.</li>
</ul>


<p>Ahh. Okay, so you have to use the same little bullet things to make them bullets. I don&rsquo;t like how my these has the bullets out of the main margin. Boogerszz. I&rsquo;ll fix that later.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[seriously forever]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/18/seriously-forever/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-18T23:08:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2014/04/18/seriously-forever</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I feel like all my posts pretty much start with the effect of, &ldquo;omg it&rsquo;s been forever since I&rsquo;ve posted!&rdquo;</p>

<p>Meh.</p>

<p>The other day, it was brought to my attention that I haven&rsquo;t been writing much anymore. Back in the day, I used to write 8 pages of daily ramblings for something like 7 years? Back when Xanga was a really cool thing that everyone wrote on. I didn&rsquo;t have many followers, nor did I really follow anyone. But I really enjoyed writing. I didn&rsquo;t really know if anyone read my stuff, but it was super cathartic, so I kept it up. Sometimes I feel like I stopped writing because I get so OCD about it all. If I don&rsquo;t write one day then I get really stressed out that I didn&rsquo;t write and then I feel all bad and gross. No bueno.</p>

<p>In any case, I originally meant for this blog to be about tech related stuff, but I really don&rsquo;t like scoping that much. I need a place to just talk about anything. Since Xanga doesn&rsquo;t seem to be up anymore, I looked at other blogging platforms and just got frustrated. So here I am again. I&rsquo;ll write about whatever is on my mind. I really don&rsquo;t think many people are going to read this stuff anyway. Whatevs.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m working on my Rad Randy app for DinoHulk. Freaking error is driving me crazy:</p>

<p>&ldquo;Application windows are expected to have a root view controller at the end of application launch&rdquo;</p>

<p>UGHHHH. I&rsquo;ll figure it out tomorrow. BLEH.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m going to make an effort at making this blog better. I guess I want to have it be my personal website too. Blah blah. Grumble ramble.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Know]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/08/07/i-know/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-07T13:06:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/08/07/i-know</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yes, yes. I know I need to update my blog more. Code Fellows is pretty intense. Oh, am I listing excuses? I hate listing excuses. I&rsquo;ll call them &ldquo;better use of my time at the current phase of my life&rdquo;:</p>

<ol>
<li>code fellows &ndash; learning all the time + projects = not a lot of time</li>
<li>work &ndash; I NEED TO EAT SO I HAVE TO WORK!</li>
<li>the heat &ndash; histamine overload. always have to make sure my body temperature doesn&rsquo;t go chaotic and make me sick. damn the sun!</li>
</ol>


<p>So yeah, in text that doesn&rsquo;t sound like much and I really should be able to get a short blurb out here and there. But I guess it&rsquo;s also that I really want to change this layout. Ughhh. I&rsquo;ll do that this weekend. Probably. Maybe. I dunno.</p>

<p>Also, the custom domain thing is killing me. It takes too long to load. Uber frustrating.</p>

<p>Until the next time I actually post. HUZZAH!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter Widget]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/07/12/twitter-widget/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-12T13:46:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/07/12/twitter-widget</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As of this current date and time, if you look to the right side column of this page, you&rsquo;ll see an embedded twitter widget. YES! I finally got around to putting that in there. I didn&rsquo;t have much on my twitter before, but I&rsquo;ve been tweeting a lot more about my learning process there, so why not?</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve installed zsh in my command prompt and it wasn&rsquo;t working with my octopress blog so I had to switch back to bash. I&rsquo;ll have to configure that somehow. But yeah I learned how to switch between them.</p>

<p>Switch to bash:</p>

<pre><code>exec bash
</code></pre>

<p>Switch to zsh</p>

<pre><code>exec zsh
</code></pre>

<p>Yeah that&rsquo;s pretty straight forward.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m really enjoying this Code Fellows bootcamp. I&rsquo;ve learned so much in such a great environment. By that I mean, the actual physical building itself and the people that surround me, but also the programming environment. It&rsquo;s so cool.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My last SQL Server class ended on Wednesday and that was pretty awesome. My instructor was trying to show us how to issue jobs off SQL Server Agent and it turned out he didn&rsquo;t have permission on his login because the school wipes the computers every night. Blah blah did stuff blah. Then eventually:</p>

<p>him: &ldquo;Alright, well, can someone connect to my server and give me rights?&rdquo;
students: <em>look around/do stuff</em>
him: &ldquo;Has anyone connected?&rdquo;
me: &ldquo;I connected.&rdquo;
him: &ldquo;Oh cool, can you set my permissions?&rdquo;
me: &ldquo;Yeah.&rdquo; <em>change login permissions and rights</em>
him: &ldquo;See, it&rsquo;s always great to have a sys admin in your back pocket. You know, just in case you lock yourself out.&rdquo;
me: &ldquo;Okay, it&rsquo;s done.&rdquo;</p>

<p>(But really I was thinking, &ldquo;OMG I&rsquo;M A SYS ADMIN! HE CALLED ME A SYS ADMIN!&rdquo;)</p>

<p>him: &ldquo;Thanks. Alright, so here we see&hellip;&rdquo;</p>

<p>And yeah, it was totally cool. It&rsquo;s great being able to utilize what you&rsquo;ve learned to help learn more stuff. UNGH! I seriously don&rsquo;t know why I love this stuff so much, but I just do.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been trying to bridge the gap between the database mindset and the programming mindset. Actually, I don&rsquo;t know if it&rsquo;s more bridging the gap or just understanding what the difference is. I&rsquo;m learning about databases and programming and for some reason I keep finding articles about how there&rsquo;s a separation. Separation of powers!?</p>

<p>I dunno.</p>

<p>Anyway, I really like my db classes, but I&rsquo;ve decided to opt out of the classes I signed up for in August because I want to focus on Code Fellows. Actually, I&rsquo;m for surely in the Silver bootcamp (I&rsquo;m currently partaking in it) and I&rsquo;m pending Gold. One of my instructors said that pretty much everyone makes it into Gold so I should just focus on working hard. Yeah I can do that. I&rsquo;m good at working hard.</p>

<p>-insert life story-</p>

<p>Sighh. Too cool. Life is good right now. Yay.</p>

<p>[histamine intolerance is relatively in check now too.]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
