<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[diana pham]]></title>
  <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-22T20:42:36-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://dianapham.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Diana Pham]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MY HEAD IS EXPANDING]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/06/22/my-head-is-expanding/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-22T20:19:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/06/22/my-head-is-expanding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seriously, I feel like my brain is pushing against my skull. I&rsquo;m soaking in so much information right now. I told someone I&rsquo;m &ldquo;drying my eyes out&rdquo; trying to learn ruby and html.</p>

<p>Yesterday, I received a message about scholarships for Code Fellows if I got into the program. I sent answers to the scholarship questions then this morning I received another message about final application questions. More like, final application problems. I have to create some stuff and holy moly bologna! The things I have to make are a little beyond my scope, but I mean, that&rsquo;s kind of what&rsquo;s making this all so fun. I&rsquo;m learning all this crazy shizzniz.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been getting really frustrated trying to figure these things out, but I think ten hours later, I&rsquo;m really getting somewhere. There are three problems and I&rsquo;ve pretty much got all of them half done. I think that&rsquo;s a good start! Haha. In theory, I know what I need to do, it&rsquo;s just making it all be real that I&rsquo;m working on. If I could use MS Access or better yet, SQL Server, I could get all this done pretty quickly, but I&rsquo;ve gotta build it all from scratch so yeah. That&rsquo;s the point! To learn!</p>

<p>Something I&rsquo;ve learned about myself is that my frustration dances and my success dances are pretty much the same; the only differences are my facial expressions. I jump up and down, express obscenities, thrash my limbs around, it looks like I&rsquo;m squinting in both dances. In my frustrated dance, I glare at everything. In my success dance I&rsquo;m smiling. Haha. I think I can model that! But I&rsquo;ll do that a little later. I gotta finish these things.</p>

<p>Huzzahhh!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just For Fun]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/06/19/just-for-fun/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-19T14:34:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/06/19/just-for-fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Currently, I have 50 bucks in my wallet. My goal for the rest of the month is not to spend any money at all (besides automatic payments for bills) and if I really have to, then that 50 bucks in my wallet will be my fund. I mean, I&rsquo;ll still have my debit and credit cards, but I really want to see if I can do this. I used to live off of so little and now that I&rsquo;m more financially secure, I&rsquo;ve been splurging on going out to eat with people.</p>

<p>Actually, yeah this monetary limitation will help with my diet because I&rsquo;ve been eating out way too much and getting hives. I&rsquo;ll have to dedicate a page to my histamine intolerance.</p>

<p>To do list for this blog:</p>

<pre><code>- landing page (index)
- change the font to the post titles
- add youtube plugin
- add disqus account
- page: singing videos
- page: art projects 
- page: histamine intolerance
- change domain
- twitter? (eh, I don't use it that much)
</code></pre>

<p>That&rsquo;s it so far.</p>

<p>Even though I didn&rsquo;t code this whole blog from scratch on my own (totally don&rsquo;t know enough to do that right now), I definitely do find joy and fulfillment in learning how to change the code as I please. Yay for technology!</p>

<p>But yeah, it&rsquo;d be so ballin&#8217; if I get into Code Fellows (I should hear back from them by the end of this week or early next week whether I get in or not). If I don&rsquo;t get in, then I&rsquo;m gonna really focus on learning more database and programming. Also, I&rsquo;m getting my diet straightened out so I need to really stick with that so I don&rsquo;t get sick so much. AND I renewed my membership for climbing so I gotta get my butt out to go exercise.</p>

<p>Ultimate frisbee this evening!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m gaining control of my life again. Thank gosh!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ice Cream Solves Everything]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/06/17/ice-cream-solves-everything/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-17T21:36:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/06/17/ice-cream-solves-everything</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Biv4YvS2yyE/Ub_nQRlpf9I/AAAAAAAAC3w/G7Q5kVhIJTs/s1600/icecream.jpg" width="600"></p>

<p>One of the questions on the Code Fellows application was something like: &ldquo;what&rsquo;s the best thing ever?&rdquo; I said ice cream. I went on to talk about how walking around with an ice cream cone was the most innocent and sincere thing ever. Also, I noted how I once saw a group of bikers walking around with ice cream cones; totally all sorts of juxtaposed adorable.</p>

<p>Anyway, I made it to the final level of applications for Code Fellows; a ten minute in-person interview. I was super excited. I emailed them my availability which was basically saying I&rsquo;d take the earliest slot they had. I ended up seeing them the next day, Friday. I was really excited and amped up to talk to these guys. I really wanted to show how dedicated and driven I was for my future, but when the interview started, I totally blanked. I&rsquo;ve always wondered about how people say they&rsquo;ve never been like &ldquo;something&rdquo; before, but then for the first time they messed up or whatever. I didn&rsquo;t know what that felt like. I&rsquo;m not sure if I&rsquo;m explaining that correctly or not. But basically, I blanked out. I seriously could not articulate when they asked me to define basic programming terminologies.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>&ldquo;What is a class?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Seriously!? That was one of the first things you learn! Why did I blank out? I fumbled around like I didn&rsquo;t know what I was talking about. I was embarrassed that I had just said I finished all these tracks on codecademy and took other online courses, but then I couldn&rsquo;t even explain a class. You don&rsquo;t really even have to know about programming to explain what a class is! Mathematical subsets! Animal classifications! Ach! I was disappointed in myself. I felt my confidence level dropping after that moment.</p>

<p>&ldquo;What is an object?&rdquo;</p>

<p>OMG. Really? Yeah. I couldn&rsquo;t think. Actually, I remember thinking the word &ldquo;static&rdquo; and I think I was probably trying to reach the word &ldquo;instance&rdquo; to use that in my definition, but jeepers creepers! What was wrong with me? I tried to merge over to where I felt more comfortable with database so I thought of the objects in databases and kind of explained it like that, but man! GAH!</p>

<p>Anyway, I tried my best to keep composure. I ended up telling them a lot about myself and what I&rsquo;ve been through to get here (to Seattle, where I am today figuratively and literally). I always mentally tell myself to tone down how much I tell people about my past, but it&rsquo;s hard because my past has been such a huge factor in shaping who I am and what I do today. Isn&rsquo;t that how it is for everyone?</p>

<p>Soooo, yeah. I think it went alright, but I didn&rsquo;t feel as confident as I normally do after my interviews. Usually, I always feel like I&rsquo;m on top of the world after an interview. This was the first one that made me feeling like I knew nothing and I just embarrassed myself. Is it because I actually really really want this?</p>

<p>Notes of the interview:</p>

<pre><code>- intros
- blogs and articles
- what is a class
- what is an object
- how does the internet work?
- my code, github, octopress (what's this line? what does this mean?)
- what code to look at
- octopress - framework, only basic modifications 
- html - what is this?
- what is a stylesheet?
- why code fellows?
- education and networking
- who brought up the idea for a woman's bootcamp
- legos, buidling things, middle school, gundam
- jiu jitsu - technical explanations vs all hands-on
- women and men think differently
- good chance
- handshakes
- sunglasses
</code></pre>

<p>Man. Alright. It&rsquo;s out of my hands now.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m gonna continue trying to learn stuff on my own regardless. I&rsquo;m trying not to be too &ldquo;meh&rdquo; about it. I just don&rsquo;t understand the mindset I was in because that honestly never happened to me before. I can now understand how other people feel when they say they don&rsquo;t understand how things that never happen end up happening. More like, things NOT happening.</p>

<p>Saturday was the last day of my SQL Level 1 course at Bellevue College. It was a good class. I learned a helluva lot. I&rsquo;m super excited for the next class in the series. I really like learning SQL. It just makes sense! It&rsquo;s so intuitive. FUNSIES! I feel like a kid in class because I&rsquo;m so wide eyed curious as to what does what. It&rsquo;s great.</p>

<p>Oh, one thing I talked about during my interview was how I didn&rsquo;t have degree and how at the moment I felt like I could get along with just networking and a skills I learn on my own. Well, on my own or through different classes not necessarily from a degree track. I still get jealous and a little bitter when people talk to me about college. Just today, one of my coworkers mentioned school to me and how I should apply to all these different schools and how it would be good for me. I knew she was just trying to help, just like most people, but I can&rsquo;t shake the annoyance I always feel.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve tried very hard and am still trying very hard to get my life to go somewhere. A formal college education just hasn&rsquo;t been the most favorable route. I ran out of my money and I&rsquo;m still not old enough to apply for financial aid by myself so I can&rsquo;t do anything about that except accept it and do something else. I&rsquo;ve come to terms with just having to do something else&mdash;on my own. I wish people would respect that and just let me be. I know they don&rsquo;t mean harm, but sheesh! Give me some credit!</p>

<p>College is a touchy subject for me. /endtopic</p>

<p>Anyway, no matter what, I know I&rsquo;m amazing. I know I have a lot of potential. I know I&rsquo;ll make something of my life. I&rsquo;ve already done so much, so why stop? I&rsquo;m tired of feeling like I&rsquo;m worthless like how people used to make me feel. I don&rsquo;t need that. AIN&rsquo;T GOT NO TIME FOR THAT! I&rsquo;VE GOT ASTHMA!</p>

<p>Haha.</p>

<p>Whether I get into Code Fellows or not, I&rsquo;ll be okay. You either win or you learn!</p>

<p>I knew that would want ice cream after my interview. I didn&rsquo;t anticipate needing to be consoled, but that&rsquo;s what&rsquo;s so great about ice cream; it can be eaten to celebrate or console. I got ice cream for both. To console my embarrassment, but also to celebrate the revelation of how far I&rsquo;ve already gotten in life.</p>

<p>Ice cream is the best.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SELECT ME FROM HERE WHERE I AM]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/06/09/select-me-from-here-where-i-am/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-09T08:21:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/06/09/select-me-from-here-where-i-am</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Is it summer yet? Nevertheless, spring/summer weather does crazy things to me. I&rsquo;ve had horrible allergies for the past three days. It hurts to keep them open. Alas, I must keep them open! There are too many beautiful things to discover and explore. Like coding!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been reading up on Octopress themes and whatnot because I do need to work on customizing this blog to be more &ldquo;me.&rdquo; (However, one friend did tell me so far it does look like &ldquo;me.&rdquo;) But yes, I&rsquo;ve got some ideas of what I want to do, but I&rsquo;ve been holding back on using my computer at home because my eyes are killing me. Staring at computers at work and at school for a total of eleven hours a day is the limit of what my eyes can take when they&rsquo;re all bloated. Haha, do eyes get bloated? Puffy? Regardless! Oh the agony I feel for them.</p>

<p>Yesterday, three broskis and I were causing havoc in my SQL class. We kept questioning everything the instructor was teaching. Years ago, I used to be annoyed at students who did that, however now I get it. I&rsquo;m not asking questions to be annoying, I&rsquo;m asking because I sincerely want to learn the right stuff and expand my mind. If I just sit back and absorb the material like a sponge, I&rsquo;m not going to learn as much. I&rsquo;m just learning how to regurgitate. I want to learn how to digest and utilize!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Basically, we were learning about INNER JOIN and during this one lab, me and the guys came up with different ways of querying the prompt. One guy wanted to bypass the middle table and go directly from one to the other. In theory, I didn&rsquo;t think this would work because the primary keys were different; I mean, that&rsquo;s kind of why there was a join table, you know? But the results showed to be the same. 17 records for both ways of querying. Long story short, we discovered that while both queries yielded 17 records, the records were different. It was pretty trippy and we tried to figure out how that happened. It was fairly simple in retrospect. We were forcing the right table to match with the left table with numbers that weren&rsquo;t necessarily supposed to match.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t know if that makes sense. I&rsquo;m not trying to be all technical here, but the point is, I really like my class and I like to open my mouth and ask questions. In that blur of fifteen minutes were we made a mess of things, I felt like I learned so much. I wrote quick scripts to support things I said in that instance. I was a little surprised at how much I had committed to my memory already.</p>

<pre><code>SELECT blah, bloob
FROM bleh.bleepblop 
WHERE blurblah
ORDER BY bloob;
</code></pre>

<p>Super fun.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m really excited to learn all this stuff. I don&rsquo;t know if I&rsquo;m going to get into the Code Fellows bootcamp, but I seriously am committing to this stuff. I want to learn how to create websites, programs and whatnot. I really enjoy working on databases too. I&rsquo;m going to stick with this database program I&rsquo;m in whether I get into Code Fellows or not. I considered stopping the classes if I got into the bootcamp, but I think it&rsquo;ll be pretty awesome to get that the database program certificate. I&rsquo;ve already learned so much and I want more. I WANT MORE!!!</p>

<p>SQL is really fun. I like learning programming languages too, but SQL is more interesting to me. I like that I&rsquo;m given a problem and I have to figure out how to retrieve the data. I understand that programming is like that too. You have a problem and you have to solve it. What I mean is, I have been something of a secretary for all my life. I&rsquo;ve always had people telling me what they wanted and to figure out how to get whatever that is for them. At work my boss says she wants a report, she doesn&rsquo;t care how I make it or get it, as long as she has the information she wants, it&rsquo;ll be good. So yeah, it&rsquo;s like a treasure hunt! Retrieving data. Haha. I haven&rsquo;t met many people who find retrieving data fun.</p>

<p>I enjoy coding too though. It&rsquo;s a bit more dry to learn, but I love throwing lines of code together and creating things like this blog or a window with interactive circles. (Note to self: upload processing projects.)</p>

<p>Anyway, I need to go rest my eyes. Whatever pollen is out there right now is killing me. The other week there were these little white fluffy things floating around everywhere. EVERYWHERE! Oh, the horror it was!</p>

<p>Fingers crossed for the Code Fellows application!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Applying to Code Fellows]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/06/06/applying-to-code-fellows/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-06T18:42:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/06/06/applying-to-code-fellows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am moments away from sending my updated application to Code Fellows. I am excited and nervous at the same time. I was in the process of getting this Octopress blog up for the past few weeks and the Code Fellows application was a huge catalyst in getting things really going.</p>

<p>So, yeah, even if I don&rsquo;t get into the women&rsquo;s bootcamp, Code Fellows has already helped me learn more about coding. YAY!</p>

<p>Wish me luck!!! :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Song]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/06/05/github-song/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-05T20:55:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/06/05/github-song</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I created this song in the middle of trying to get this blog up and running. Enjoy!</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/QlpzTM4euCQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Will Work]]></title>
    <link href="http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/06/05/this-will-work/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-05T19:29:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dianapham.github.io/blog/2013/06/05/this-will-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi,</p>

<p>My name is Diana and I really, times one million, want this first post to actually work.</p>

<p>Sincerely,</p>

<p>Diana</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
